AYOBAMI **AJIBOLA**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Ini Bassey street Arab road Kubwa, Abuja, Nigeria · +234 8031957690

ayobamiajibola46@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

Dedicated and enthusiastic developer with four years of experience in web-based user interactions. I have extensive experience working with JavaScript, as well as its runtime environment and library (**Node.js and React.js**). My work is guided by the goal of creating solutions that use the best technologies to produce better user experiences using react and creating robust APIs with the RESTful concept.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2021 - TILL DATE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, A'MOBI LTD

- I develop and maintain effective databases and applications.
- Create appealing visual design for application front ends.
- Define and document AWS best practices and strategies regarding application deployment and infrastructure maintenance

NOV 2019 - MARCH 2021

INTERN, A'MOBI LTD

- I Assisted developers in project and development of new features.
- Participated in projects that taught me best practices for architecting, designing, and development.

MARCH 2017 - APR 2019

FRONT END DEVELOPER, TEETYTECH

I Developed and implemented front end architecture to support user interface concept, worked closely with the UI/UX designer to transform designs into code.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2015

B.LIS, UNIVERSITY OF MAIDUGURI, BORNO STATE, NIGERIA

Bachelor of Library and Information Science

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- NodeJS
- ReactJS

- PSQL
- MogoDB
- Sequelize
- AWS

- GIT
- REST API
- Redux
- Typescript

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2022

BACKEND DEVELOPER, PO2023-SMART-APP, ABUJA, NIGERIA

I developed parts of the backend codebase and API's for this project. This solution aims to reduce election fraud in my home country Nigeria, by enabling party officials to report live election results in real time for transparency.

2019 - TILL DATE

FACILITATOR, SHE ICT SOCIETY (SIS), ABUJA, NIGERIA

I volunteer with SIS to teach and make computer education applicable, easy, and free for young girls aged 8 to 16 in rural Abuja, Nigeria, with a mentorship program integrated for their self-development and growth.